# **Stephen Thompson**

Location: Chicago, IL 60647

Portfolio: <a href="https://sgthompson.herokuapp.com">https://sgthompson.herokuapp.com</a>

Phone: (410) 688-1617 | Email: drsgthompson@gmail.com

GitHub: http://github.com/SThompsonChicago | Linkedin.linkedin.com/in/drsgthompson

# Summary

Full-stack web developer living in Chicago. PhD in applied mathematics. Over five years of experience teaching mathematics and statistics, and three years writing code. Published research in peer-reviewed journals on fixed-point theory, mathematical epidemiology, differential equations and economics. Recently finished the full stack boot camp at Northwestern University.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript, Node.js, Python, React.js, MERN stack, Handlebars, Express.js, MVC, Bulma, SQL, Git, HTML, CSS, jQuery, MongoDB, NoSQL, Visual Studio and GraphQL.

## **Soft Skills**

Patient, innovative, and able to see the big picture.

#### **Projects**

React.js Macroeconomic Forecaster: React.js application that allows user to choose parameters for a macroeconomic model, run simulations, and view the results as an animation as the model is being solved (uses Runge-Kutta method).

Deployed app: <a href="https://sthompsonchicago.github.io/macro-disequilibrium/">https://sthompsonchicago.github.io/macro-disequilibrium/</a> GitHub repo: <a href="https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/macro-disequilibrium/">https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/macro-disequilibrium/</a>

MERN Blog: Full-stack application that allows a user to create an account, write blog posts and view posts by others. Created using the MERN stack. Uses a MongoDB database to store posts and other information, and makes queries with GraphQL. Safely stores passwords using bcrypt library. Back end built with Apollo server.

Deployed app: <a href="https://vast-mountain-43651.herokuapp.com/">https://vast-mountain-43651.herokuapp.com/</a> GitHub repo: <a href="https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/mern-blog">https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/mern-blog</a>

Python Simulation Space: Full-stack app created with Python/Django. Allows user to choose simulation models from a MySQL database, and then run them within the web browser.

Deployed app: https://singwithsims.herokuapp.com/

GitHub repo: https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/python-simulation-space

### **Education**

Certificate, Full-Stack Web Development Northwestern University, 2021

Doctor of Philosophy, Applied Mathematics University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC), 2013

# **Professional Experience**

Mathematics Instructor, 2015-2021

University of Maryland, Baltimore County (Baltimore, Maryland)

- Developed student mastery of differential equations, linear algebra and calculus.
- Instructed classes with up to 120 students.

High School Teacher, 2019-2020

Baltimore City Public Schools (Baltimore, Maryland)

• Motivated over 60 students to understand algebra and meet graduation requirements.

Affiliate Faculty, 2017-2019

Loyola University, Maryland (Baltimore, Maryland)

- Taught a variety of undergraduate calculus courses.
- Helped classes of 20+ students understand complex integration strategies.